<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[PLANTS + PERKS]]></title><description><![CDATA[PLANTS + PERKS]]></description><link>https://www.plantsandperks.com/blog</link><generator>RSS for Node</generator><lastBuildDate>Fri, 04 Oct 2024 09:04:08 GMT</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.plantsandperks.com/blog-feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title><![CDATA[Do I even need a sustainable benefits offering?]]></title><description><![CDATA[Introducing a sustainable employee benefits platform is a crucial step that companies must take to ensure their employees are well taken...]]></description><link>https://www.plantsandperks.com/post/do-i-even-need-a-sustainable-benefits-offering</link><guid isPermaLink="false">63fdea085dff6ef6e4650909</guid><pubDate>Tue, 28 Feb 2023 11:53:48 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/nsplsh_b17742acb7d94af39dc470797a60f848~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><dc:creator>Chloe Sweden</dc:creator><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><br /></p>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/nsplsh_b17742acb7d94af39dc470797a60f848~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png"></figure>
<p>Introducing a sustainable employee benefits platform is a crucial step that companies must take to ensure their employees are well taken care of. By doing so, the company can not only improve the wellbeing of their employees but also take a leadership role in promoting sustainability and social responsibility.</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p>First and foremost, introducing a sustainable employee benefits platform can help people achieve a healthier and more sustainable lifestyle. With access to wellness programs, eco-friendly commute options, and healthy meal plans, employees can make informed decisions about their health and reduce their carbon footprint. This can lead to higher job satisfaction, increased employee engagement, and better work-life balance.</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p>Furthermore, sustainable employee benefits can be a powerful tool for attracting and retaining top talent. Today&apos;s workforce is increasingly environmentally conscious and socially aware, and they want to work for companies that share their values. By offering sustainable employee benefits, companies can show that they care about their employees&apos; wellbeing and the planet, making them an attractive employer for top talent.</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p>But what&apos;s wrong with your current approach to employee benefits? </p>
<p><br /></p>
<p>Many companies offer traditional benefits such as health insurance and retirement plans but often overlook sustainability and social responsibility. This approach not only fails to address the current societal challenges but can also lead to negative consequences such as reduced productivity, increased healthcare costs, and turnover rates.</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p>By introducing a sustainable employee benefits platform, companies can position themselves as leaders in the movement towards sustainability and social responsibility. They can be bold and outrageous in their approach by offering benefits such as paid time off for volunteering, electric vehicle incentives, or green energy subsidies. This not only sends a clear message to employees and customers about the company&apos;s values but also creates a positive impact on the planet.</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p>In conclusion, introducing a sustainable employee benefits platform is a win-win for both employees and companies. It helps employees achieve a healthier and more sustainable lifestyle while also positioning the company as a leader in the movement towards sustainability and social responsibility. By taking a bold and outrageous approach, companies can differentiate themselves from their competitors and create a positive impact on the world.</p>]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Tips for Creating a Sustainable Employee Benefits Programme That Fits Your Company Culture]]></title><description><![CDATA[As companies increasingly prioritise sustainability, many are incorporating sustainable employee benefits programmes into their...]]></description><link>https://www.plantsandperks.com/post/tips-for-creating-a-sustainable-employee-benefits-programme-that-fits-your-company-culture</link><guid isPermaLink="false">63f8e0cca0dfe0454f67d09f</guid><pubDate>Fri, 24 Feb 2023 16:08:35 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/11062b_1b9e55a4db784c3487bda8f044deda8f~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><dc:creator>Chloe Sweden</dc:creator><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><br /></p>
<p><br /></p>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/11062b_1b9e55a4db784c3487bda8f044deda8f~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png"></figure>
<p><br /></p>
<p><span style="color: #374151;">As companies increasingly prioritise sustainability, many are incorporating sustainable employee benefits programmes into their offerings. These programmes not only demonstrate a company&apos;s commitment to sustainability but can also improve employee satisfaction and retention. However, creating a sustainable employee benefits program that fits your company culture can be challenging. </span></p>
<p><span style="color: #374151;">Here at PLANTS + PERKS we will provide tips for creating a programme that aligns with your company values and culture.</span></p>
<p><br /></p>
<p><span style="color: #374151;">Understand Your Company Culture</span></p>
<p><br /></p>
<p><span style="color: #374151;">The first step in creating a sustainable employee benefits program is understanding your company culture. Consider your company values and the type of culture you want to cultivate. Are you a tech startup with a casual atmosphere, or a law firm with a more formal environment? Understanding your company culture will help you determine the types of sustainable benefits that will be most successful in your workplace.</span></p>
<p><br /></p>
<p><span style="color: #374151;">Involve Your Employees</span></p>
<p><br /></p>
<p><span style="color: #374151;">When designing a sustainable employee benefits programme, it&apos;s important to involve your employees in the process. Conduct surveys or focus groups to gather feedback on what benefits would be most appealing and effective. Additionally, involving your employees in the programme design can increase engagement and adoption rates.</span></p>
<p><br /></p>
<p><span style="color: #374151;">Offer a Range of Benefits</span></p>
<p><br /></p>
<p><span style="color: #374151;">A sustainable employee benefits program can include a range of benefits that align with your company culture. For example, here at PLANTS + PERKS we are introducing a wide range of extra ways to support your employees beyond our core perks and engagement product. Additionally, consider offering benefits that align with sustainability, such as public transit subsidies, composting programs, or reusable water bottles.</span></p>
<p><br /></p>
<p><span style="color: #374151;">Communicate the Programme Effectively</span></p>
<p><br /></p>
<p><span style="color: #374151;">Effective communication is key to the success of any employee benefits program. Clearly communicate the benefits of the program, how to enrol, and any deadlines or requirements. Additionally, consider incorporating sustainability messaging into your company culture and communications to reinforce the importance of sustainability to your employees. Luckily with PLANTS + PERKS you get full account management support and one of our amazing team will not only help oversee an amazing launch but hold your hand throughout. </span></p>
<p><br /></p>
<p><span style="color: #374151;">Measure the Impact</span></p>
<p><br /></p>
<p><span style="color: #374151;">To ensure the success of your sustainable employee benefits program, it&apos;s important to measure its impact. Consider tracking enrollment rates, employee satisfaction, and any associated cost savings. Additionally, gathering feedback from employees can help you make adjustments and improvements to the programme over time.</span></p>
<p><span style="color: #374151;">Creating a sustainable employee benefits program that aligns with your company culture can be challenging, but it&apos;s an important step in demonstrating your commitment to sustainability and improving employee satisfaction and retention. By understanding your company culture, involving your employees, offering a range of benefits, communicating effectively, and measuring the impact, you can create a programme that contributes to a more sustainable future for all.</span></p>
<p><br /></p>]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[The ROI of Sustainable Employee Benefits: The Long-Term Benefits for Your Business]]></title><description><![CDATA[Sustainable employee benefits are becoming more popular among companies that are committed to reducing their carbon footprint and...]]></description><link>https://www.plantsandperks.com/post/the-roi-of-sustainable-employee-benefits-the-long-term-benefits-for-your-business</link><guid isPermaLink="false">63f8de38ea7aed60c37e4237</guid><pubDate>Fri, 24 Feb 2023 15:58:00 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/nsplsh_f7b4423c9d6e4bbc9848a9412f461185~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><dc:creator>Alice Long</dc:creator><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><br /></p>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/nsplsh_f7b4423c9d6e4bbc9848a9412f461185~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png"></figure>
<p><br /></p>
<p><span style="color: #374151;">Sustainable employee benefits are becoming more popular among companies that are committed to reducing their carbon footprint and contributing to a healthier planet. However, sustainable benefits are not just about being socially responsible; they can also be a powerful tool in boosting the bottom line. </span></p>
<p><span style="color: #374151;">Here are just a few reasons offering sustainable employee benefits can deliver a significant return on investment and long-term benefits to your business.</span></p>
<p><span style="color: #374151;">Improved Employee Productivity</span></p>
<p><span style="color: #374151;">Sustainable employee benefits can also have a positive impact on employee productivity. For example, offering perks programmes such as PLANTS + PERKS can improve employee wellbeing and reduce stress, leading to higher levels of productivity. Additionally, providing sustainable food options can improve employee nutrition and reduce the risk of chronic diseases, leading to fewer sick days and higher productivity levels. A study by the World Health Organization found that a healthy diet can improve cognitive function and productivity.</span></p>
<p><span style="color: #374151;">Attracting and Retaining Talent</span></p>
<p><span style="color: #374151;">Sustainable employee benefits can also help companies attract and retain talent. Offering sustainable benefits demonstrates a company&apos;s commitment to sustainability and can attract like-minded employees who share the same values. Additionally, offering sustainable benefits can improve employee satisfaction and retention. A study by Deloitte found that employees who feel their company is committed to sustainability are more likely to stay with the company long-term, reducing turnover and the associated costs of recruiting and training new employees.</span></p>
<p><span style="color: #374151;">Brand Reputation</span></p>
<p><span style="color: #374151;">Sustainable employee benefits can also improve a company&apos;s brand reputation, leading to increased customer loyalty and sales. Consumers are becoming more environmentally conscious and are more likely to support companies that share their values. Offering sustainable benefits demonstrates a company&apos;s commitment to sustainability and can attract environmentally conscious consumers.</span></p>
<p>
</p>
<p>
</p>
<p><br /></p>]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[The Environmental and Social Impact of Sustainable Employee Benefits]]></title><description><![CDATA[Sustainable employee benefits are becoming more prevalent in the corporate world as companies strive to become more socially and...]]></description><link>https://www.plantsandperks.com/post/the-environmental-and-social-impact-of-sustainable-employee-benefits</link><guid isPermaLink="false">63f8db8cca3d708f9d641514</guid><pubDate>Fri, 24 Feb 2023 15:46:18 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/nsplsh_d9fb7eaec2d64925b326008cada6b5a8~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><dc:creator>Ellen Chng</dc:creator><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><br /></p>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/nsplsh_d9fb7eaec2d64925b326008cada6b5a8~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png"></figure>
<p><br /></p>
<p><span style="color: #374151;">Sustainable employee benefits are becoming more prevalent in the corporate world as companies strive to become more socially and environmentally responsible. These benefits not only contribute to a more sustainable future but can also have a positive impact on employee well-being and satisfaction. </span></p>
<p><span style="color: #374151;">Reducing Carbon Footprint</span></p>
<p><span style="color: #374151;">One of the most significant environmental benefits of sustainable employee benefits is the reduction in carbon footprint. For example, incentivising sustainable commuting can reduce the number of employees driving to work, thereby reducing the carbon emissions associated with commuting. According to a study by the Union of Concerned Scientists, if just one in ten Americans were to take public transportation to work, this would reduce carbon emissions by 10% annually. </span></p>
<p><span style="color: #374151;">Improving Employee Well-Being</span></p>
<p><span style="color: #374151;">Sustainable employee benefits can also have a positive impact on employee well-being and satisfaction. For example, providing healthy and sustainable food options and recipes can improve employee nutrition and reduce the risk of chronic diseases. A study by the World Health Organization found that a healthy diet can reduce the risk of non-communicable diseases such as diabetes and cardiovascular disease. </span></p>
<p><span style="color: #374151;">Attracting and Retaining Talent</span></p>
<p><span style="color: #374151;">Sustainable employee benefits can also help companies attract and retain talent. According to a study by Cone Communications, 71 percent of millennials consider a company&apos;s environmental and social commitment when making employment decisions. Offering sustainable benefits demonstrates a company&apos;s commitment to sustainability and can attract like-minded employees who share the same values. Additionally, offering sustainable benefits can improve employee satisfaction and retention. A study by Deloitte found that employees who feel their company is committed to sustainability are more likely to stay with the company long-term.</span></p>
<p><span style="color: #374151;">Sustainable employee benefits like PLANTS + PERKS have a significant impact on both the environment and employee well-being. They can reduce carbon emissions, improve employee nutrition and mental health, and attract and retain talented employees who share the same values. As more companies prioritise sustainability, sustainable employee benefits will become increasingly important in creating a more sustainable future for all.</span></p>
<p><br /></p>]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[The Role of Sustainable Employee Benefits in Attracting and Retaining Talent]]></title><description><![CDATA[Sustainable employee benefits are becoming increasingly popular as companies strive to reduce their carbon footprint and contribute to a...]]></description><link>https://www.plantsandperks.com/post/the-role-of-sustainable-employee-benefits-in-attracting-and-retaining-talent</link><guid isPermaLink="false">63f8d95d4c34a18cfc6e9ada</guid><pubDate>Fri, 24 Feb 2023 15:38:06 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/nsplsh_5670636754454b65724551~mv2_d_5889_3931_s_4_2.jpg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><dc:creator>Chloe Sweden</dc:creator><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><br /></p>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/nsplsh_5670636754454b65724551~mv2_d_5889_3931_s_4_2.jpg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png"></figure>
<p><span style="color: #374151;">Sustainable employee benefits are becoming increasingly popular as companies strive to reduce their carbon footprint and contribute to a healthier planet. However, sustainable benefits are not just about being socially responsible; they can also be a powerful tool in attracting and retaining talent.</span></p>
<p><span style="color: #374151;">The Importance of Sustainable Employee Benefits</span></p>
<p><span style="color: #374151;">Employees today are more environmentally conscious than ever before. They want to work for companies that share their values and are committed to making a positive impact on the environment. By offering sustainable employee benefits, companies can demonstrate their commitment to sustainability and attract like-minded employees.</span></p>
<p><span style="color: #374151;">Moreover, sustainable benefits can also help companies retain their employees. Employees who feel valued and supported by their employer are more likely to stay with the company long-term. Offering sustainable benefits shows employees that their employer cares about their well-being and is committed to creating a positive work environment.</span></p>
<p><span style="color: #374151;">Types of Sustainable Employee Benefits</span></p>
<p><span style="color: #374151;">There are numerous types of sustainable employee benefits that companies can offer to attract and retain talent. Some examples include:</span></p>
<ol>
  <li><p><span style="color: #374151;">Sustainable transportation options: Companies can offer incentives for employees to use alternative modes of transportation, such as public transit, biking, or walking. This can reduce the number of employees driving to work, which can significantly lower the company&apos;s carbon footprint.</span></p></li>
  <li><p><span style="color: #374151;">Remote working: Companies can offer remote working or hybrid options to employees, allowing them to work from home or another location. This can reduce the number of employees driving to work, thereby lowering the company&apos;s carbon footprint and helping employees save on commuting costs.</span></p></li>
  <li><p><span style="color: #374151;">Sustainable food options: Companies can provide sustainable food options in their cafeterias and vending machines. This can include locally sourced, organic, and plant-based options, which can reduce the carbon emissions associated with food transportation and production.</span></p></li>
  <li><p><span style="color: #374151;">Green education and training: Companies can provide education and training programs to employees to raise awareness about sustainable practices and encourage them to adopt more sustainable behaviours both at work and in their personal lives.</span></p></li>
  <li><p><span style="color: #374151;">Eco-friendly benefits: Companies can offer benefits such as sustainable perks like PLANTS + PERKS. These benefits can help employees offset their personal carbon footprints and contribute to the company&apos;s sustainability goals.</span></p></li>
</ol>
<p><span style="color: #374151;">In conclusion, sustainable employee benefits can be a powerful tool in attracting and retaining talent allowing companies to demonstrate their commitment to sustainability and create a positive work environment that attracts and retains talented employees who share their values.</span></p>
<p><br /></p>]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[The Connection Between Employee Happiness and Sustainability in the Workplace]]></title><description><![CDATA[Creating a sustainable workplace is not just about reducing environmental impact; it is also about creating a workplace that supports...]]></description><link>https://www.plantsandperks.com/post/the-connection-between-employee-happiness-and-sustainability-in-the-workplace</link><guid isPermaLink="false">63f8d4a23f4a59cbd32a37c1</guid><pubDate>Fri, 24 Feb 2023 15:17:09 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/nsplsh_90ab8b0b7ad64d47af2967e665ee8220~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><dc:creator>Lola Wright</dc:creator><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><br /></p>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/nsplsh_90ab8b0b7ad64d47af2967e665ee8220~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png"></figure>
<p><br /></p>
<p><span style="color: #374151;">Creating a sustainable workplace is not just about reducing environmental impact; it is also about creating a workplace that supports employee well-being and happiness. When employees are happy, they are more engaged, productive, and committed to their work. This, in turn, can lead to increased profitability and success for the company. Moreover, a happy and healthy workforce is essential for achieving long-term sustainability.</span></p>
<p><span style="color: #374151;">Here are some ways in which employee happiness and sustainability are connected:</span></p>
<p><br /></p>
<p><span style="color: #374151;">Health and wellness programmes</span></p>
<p><br /></p>
<p><span style="color: #374151;">Sustainable workplaces often prioritise health and wellness programmes that encourage physical activity, healthy eating, and stress reduction. Such programmes can lead to a healthier workforce, lower healthcare costs, and improved productivity. Additionally, promoting healthy habits can reduce absenteeism and increase job satisfaction, resulting in happier employees.</span></p>
<p><br /></p>
<p><span style="color: #374151;">Work-life balance</span></p>
<p><br /></p>
<p><span style="color: #374151;">Sustainable workplaces also recognize the importance of work-life balance. They provide employees with flexible working hours, remote work options, and other benefits that allow them to balance work and personal responsibilities. This helps reduce stress and burnout, leading to more motivated and productive employees.</span></p>
<p><br /></p>
<p><span style="color: #374151;">Purpose-driven work</span></p>
<p><br /></p>
<p><span style="color: #374151;">Employees are more likely to be happy and engaged when they feel that their work is meaningful and aligned with their values. Sustainable workplaces often prioritise purpose-driven work by promoting social and environmental responsibility. This can create a sense of pride and fulfilment among employees, resulting in higher job satisfaction and retention.</span></p>
<p><br /></p>
<p><span style="color: #374151;">Positive workplace culture</span></p>
<p><br /></p>
<p><span style="color: #374151;">Sustainable workplaces prioritise positive workplace culture by promoting collaboration, respect, and inclusivity. A positive workplace culture can foster a sense of belonging and support among employees, resulting in a happier and more productive workforce.</span></p>
<p><span style="color: #374151;">Walking the Walk</span></p>
<p><span style="color: #374151;">In order to fully embed sustainable practices into your organisation employees, especially Gen Z and Millennial talent, are looking for companies that walk the walk. By introducing schemes like PLANTS + PERKS, employees can be rewarded for their commitment to reducing their impact as well as fostering a sense of employee wellbeing and increased engagement.</span></p>
<p><br /></p>]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[How to Implement Sustainable Employee Benefits: A Step-by-Step Guide]]></title><description><![CDATA[In today's world, sustainability is not just limited to the environment, it also applies to the way we operate our businesses and treat...]]></description><link>https://www.plantsandperks.com/post/how-to-implement-sustainable-employee-benefits-a-step-by-step-guide</link><guid isPermaLink="false">63f8ce514c34a18cfc6e8f7d</guid><pubDate>Fri, 24 Feb 2023 14:50:07 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/nsplsh_8818e7e87c324ce79304e28643954542~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><dc:creator>Henry Fettes</dc:creator><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><br /></p>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/nsplsh_8818e7e87c324ce79304e28643954542~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png"></figure>
<p><br /></p>
<p><br /></p>
<p>In today&apos;s world, sustainability is not just limited to the environment, it also applies to the way we operate our businesses and treat our employees. One way to ensure sustainability in the workplace is to implement sustainable employee benefits. Sustainable employee benefits not only benefit the employees, but they also contribute to the overall sustainability of the business. Here at PLANTS + PERKS  we will provide you with a step-by-step guide on how to implement sustainable employee benefits.</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p>Step 1: Evaluate your current benefits programme</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p>The first step in implementing sustainable employee benefits is to evaluate your current benefits programme. Review the benefits you currently offer to your employees and determine which ones are sustainable and which ones are not. Identify the benefits that are not sustainable and consider alternative options that are more sustainable.</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p>Step 2: Conduct research</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p>Conduct research to identify sustainable employee benefits that are relevant to your business and your employees. Look for benefits that align with your company values and mission, and that are also attractive to your employees. Cycle to Work schemes and EV leasing schemes are great but limited in scope. Benefits like PLANTS + PERKS can operate globally and have mass appeal.</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p>Step 3: Create a plan</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p>Create a plan for implementing sustainable employee benefits. The plan should include a timeline, budget, and a list of benefits to be offered. Identify the departments and individuals responsible for implementing the plan and establish metrics to track the success of the programme.</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p>Step 4: Communicate with employees</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p>Communicate the new sustainable employee benefits program to your employees. Explain the benefits and how they align with your company values and mission. Encourage employees to take advantage of the new benefits and provide them with the necessary resources and support to do so. With PLANTS + PERKS you get full account management support so you can lean on our team to help with the rollout and ongoing engagement.</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p>Step 5: Monitor and adjust</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p>Monitor the programme to ensure its success and make adjustments as needed. Collect feedback from employees to determine which benefits are most popular and which ones need improvement. Use this feedback to make adjustments to the programme to ensure its long-term sustainability.</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p>Implementing sustainable employee benefits is an essential part of building a sustainable business. By following this step-by-step guide, you can create a programme that benefits both your employees and your business, while also contributing to a more sustainable future. With PLANTS + PERKS by your side we guarantee a seamless and effortless way to embed sustainable benefits into your organisation. </p>
<p><br /></p>]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[The Top 5 Benefits of Sustainable Employee Perks for Your Business]]></title><description><![CDATA[As the world becomes more environmentally conscious and socially responsible, businesses are looking for ways to incorporate...]]></description><link>https://www.plantsandperks.com/post/the-top-5-benefits-of-sustainable-employee-perks-for-your-business</link><guid isPermaLink="false">63f8cbdc3f4a59cbd32a2e92</guid><pubDate>Fri, 24 Feb 2023 14:41:07 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/nsplsh_6a4642574f616f532d376f~mv2_d_6000_4000_s_4_2.jpg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><dc:creator>Henry Fettes</dc:creator><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><br /></p>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/nsplsh_6a4642574f616f532d376f~mv2_d_6000_4000_s_4_2.jpg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png"></figure>
<p><br /></p>
<p><br /></p>
<p><span style="color: #374151;">As the world becomes more environmentally conscious and socially responsible, businesses are looking for ways to incorporate sustainability into their operations. An easy way to do this is by offering sustainable employee benefits, which not only promote sustainability but also benefit the company in various ways. Here at PLANTS + PERKS we explore the top 5 benefits of sustainable employee benefits for your business.</span></p>
<p><br /></p>
<p><span style="color: #374151;">1. Attract and Retain Talent</span></p>
<p><br /></p>
<p><span style="color: #374151;">Sustainable employee benefits are highly attractive to employees who value sustainability and want to work for a company that shares their values. By offering sustainable employee benefits, businesses can attract and retain top talent who are passionate about sustainability and want to work for a company that is committed to making a positive impact on the environment and society.</span></p>
<p><span style="color: #374151;">Increase </span></p>
<p><br /></p>
<p><span style="color: #374151;">2. Employee Engagement</span></p>
<p><br /></p>
<p><span style="color: #374151;">Sustainable employee benefits can help increase employee engagement by providing employees with opportunities to get involved in sustainability initiatives and make a positive impact on the environment and society. This can lead to increased job satisfaction, improved morale, and a stronger sense of purpose among employees.</span></p>
<p><br /></p>
<p><span style="color: #374151;">3. Improve Brand Image</span></p>
<p><br /></p>
<p><span style="color: #374151;">Offering sustainable employee benefits can improve a company&apos;s brand image by demonstrating its commitment to sustainability and corporate social responsibility. This can enhance the company&apos;s reputation, attract socially conscious customers, and even help to attract investors who are looking for socially responsible businesses to invest in.</span></p>
<p><br /></p>
<p><span style="color: #374151;">4. Reduce Costs</span></p>
<p><br /></p>
<p><span style="color: #374151;">Sustainable employee benefits can also help businesses reduce costs in various ways. For example, incentivising eco-friendly transportation options can help reduce transportation costs and carbon emissions. Implementing energy-efficient measures can help reduce utility bills. Providing healthy and sustainable food options can help reduce healthcare costs by promoting healthier eating habits among employees.</span></p>
<p><br /></p>
<p><span style="color: #374151;">5. Lower Carbon Footprint</span></p>
<p><br /></p>
<p><span style="color: #374151;">Sustainable employee benefits can help contribute to overall company sustainability goals. By engaging employees to lower their own individual footprints companies can benefit from lower Scope 3 emissions and a more heightened awareness and commitment to improving society and the environment as a whole.</span></p>
<p><br /></p>
<p><span style="color: #374151;">By incorporating sustainability into their employee benefits programs through schemes like PLANTS + PERKS, businesses can make a positive impact on the environment and society while also benefiting their bottom line.</span></p>
<p><br /></p>]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[5 easy, healthy food swaps that help the planet]]></title><description><![CDATA[Written In Partnership With: ZENB. Sourcing foods which are the healthier option can be hard enough, but when we throw in making choices...]]></description><link>https://www.plantsandperks.com/post/5-easy-healthy-food-swaps-that-help-the-planet</link><guid isPermaLink="false">63e36bdf9b9417f94972ae3c</guid><pubDate>Wed, 08 Feb 2023 10:15:10 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/5727b1_a29637c001124206911896e408edab61~mv2.png/v1/fit/w_1000,h_698,al_c,q_80/file.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><dc:creator>Alice Long</dc:creator><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>Written In Partnership With: ZENB.</strong></p>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/5727b1_a29637c001124206911896e408edab61~mv2.png/v1/fit/w_1000,h_698,al_c,q_80/file.png"></figure>
<p><br /></p>
<p>Sourcing foods which are the healthier option can be hard enough, but when we throw in making choices about the health of the planet as well it can seem like an even more complex puzzle to try and solve.</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p>You may not think that small changes to your everyday diet will make a difference, but think again. Choosing more sustainable foods and incorporating them into your daily diet is actually a really simple way to transition to eating in a way that is kind to both your body and the planet. </p>
<p><br /></p>
<p>Here are some ideas to help you on your way to adopting a more sustainable lifestyle through what you consume:
</p>
<p><strong>1. Eat </strong><a href="https://www.awin1.com/cread.php?awinmid=25893&awinaffid=1102079&clickref=PLANTS%2BPERKS&ued=https%3A%2F%2Fzenb.co.uk%2F" target="_blank"><strong>yellow pea pasta</strong></a><strong> instead of wheat pasta</strong></p>
<p><br /></p>
<p>No matter the shape or size, it’s no secret that all kinds of pasta taste delicious. But, have you ever considered the environmental impact that wheat pasta has on the planet? </p>
<p><br /></p>
<p>Research conducted in 2020 (1), shows that traditional pasta – made from wheat – very much falls into our modern food system characterised by unsustainable agricultural practices that use environmentally damaging nitrogen fertilisers and over-consumption of nutrient-poor foods that contribute to non-communicable disease and malnutrition.</p>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/5727b1_2d1a56e1b675497399a2fee2f539a2bd~mv2.png/v1/fit/w_798,h_533,al_c,q_80/file.png"></figure>
<p><br /></p>
<p>Instead, <a href="https://www.awin1.com/cread.php?awinmid=25893&awinaffid=1102079&clickref=PLANTS%2BPERKS&ued=https%3A%2F%2Fzenb.co.uk%2F" target="_blank">yellow pea pasta</a> negates many of the issues that are brought about by producing wheat. Not only does yellow pea pasta require less water to grow than wheat (2), creating a greener choice for the planet, but it also increases soil microbial diversity and heralds health benefits such as being higher in protein, fibre and potassium.</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p>Made from 100% yellow peas, <a href="https://www.awin1.com/cread.php?awinmid=25893&awinaffid=1102079&clickref=PLANTS%2BPERKS&ued=https%3A%2F%2Fzenb.co.uk%2F" target="_blank">ZENB pasta</a> is a brand offering an exciting new twist on a much-loved kitchen staple. Easy to cook and full of nutrients, <a href="https://www.awin1.com/cread.php?awinmid=25893&awinaffid=1102079&clickref=PLANTS%2BPERKS&ued=https%3A%2F%2Fzenb.co.uk%2F" target="_blank">ZENB pasta</a> is a tasty alternative you need to try with all your favourite pasta dishes. </p>
<p><br /></p>
<p><a href="https://www.awin1.com/cread.php?awinmid=25893&awinaffid=1102079&clickref=PLANTS%2BPERKS&ued=https%3A%2F%2Fzenb.co.uk%2F" target="_blank"><strong>You can now get 40% off your first ZENB order with code </strong></a><a href="https://www.awin1.com/cread.php?awinmid=25893&awinaffid=1102079&clickref=PLANTS%2BPERKS&ued=https%3A%2F%2Fzenb.co.uk%2F" target="_blank"><em><strong>PLANTS</strong></em></a><strong>.</strong></p>
<p><br /></p>
<p><br /></p>
<p><strong>2. Start using extra virgin olive oil</strong></p>
<p><br /></p>
<p>With almost every recipe starting with ‘add a splash of oil to a pan’, it’s highly likely that you’ve got one or two cooking oils in your kitchen cupboard. But not all of these cooking oils are made equal. Different types of oils have different effects on the environment and on your body, so choosing which one to use can be difficult.</p>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/5727b1_e46e328a76b841fbaa93db1fa5f4a48a~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png"></figure>
<p>Out of all the oils available, the most destructive is palm oil - this should be avoided at all costs. Not only is it responsible for the destruction of the world’s rainforests but for driving orangutans to the brink of extinction. </p>
<p><br /></p>
<p>We would recommend using extra virgin olive oil that’s organic and fair trade for cooking. One key advantage of extra virgin olive oil when compared to other mainstream cooking oils is the olive tree’s ability to act as a carbon sink. This means that olive trees trap more carbon from the atmosphere than they release (4).
</p>
<p><strong>3. Switch cow’s milk to plant-based milk</strong></p>
<p><br /></p>
<p>One of the simplest, planet-friendly swaps you can make is switching cow’s milk to plant-based milk. There is currently a plethora of plant-based milk on our supermarket shelves and at our local coffee shops for you to choose from.</p>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/5727b1_71d8a908ab4b467c8fc7f3b91717e41c~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png"></figure>
<p>When looking at which plant-based milk is best for the environment, there is no ‘best in all categories’ choice, so it really does depend on what measure you care most about (i.e. land use, water use, greenhouse gas emissions etc). But, it’s important to understand that any plant-based milk that you do decide to use - we’d recommend almond milk, oat milk or soya milk - has a much lighter environmental impact than dairy.
</p>
<p><strong>4. Swap meat for plant-based alternatives</strong></p>
<p><br /></p>
<p>Raising livestock generates ~14.5% of global greenhouse gas emissions (3), the second highest source of emissions behind fossil fuels and greater than all transportation combined. It also uses about 70% of agricultural land and is one of the leading causes of deforestation, biodiversity loss, and water pollution.</p>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/5727b1_6c2f90498dcb4a3f87c04d02111f11d2~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png"></figure>
<p>Reducing your consumption of meat is one of the most effective ways to reduce your environmental impact on the planet. By just switching out some of your meat products for plant-based alternatives such as tofu, <a href="https://shop.tibatempeh.com/" target="_blank">tempeh</a>, <a href="https://bravefoods.co.uk/" target="_blank">pulses</a> and <a href="https://www.awin1.com/cread.php?awinmid=22512&awinaffid=1102079&clickref=PLANTS%2BPERKS&ued=https%3A%2F%2Fplanty.uk%2F" target="_blank">faux meat</a>, you can help tackle the climate crisis one bite at a time.
</p>
<p><strong>5. Swap cheese for plant-based cheese</strong></p>
<p><br /></p>
<p>This is a hard one, we know! But you&apos;d be surprised how unsustainable cheese production is. Cheese has a high carbon footprint with 1 pound of cheese requiring more than 10 pounds of milk! This means it generates the third highest greenhouse gas emissions from food, right after beef and lamb. </p>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/5727b1_9583f852c5f1455e8cdf653f3d1398b2~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png"></figure>
<p>As it turns out, plant-based cheese is a great alternative to cheese produced from dairy. It’s always been one of the most difficult substitutes to match up to the real deal, yet there have been incredible strides in recent months made in its taste and texture of it. </p>
<p><br /></p>
<p>And in terms of health, plant-based cheese is also a great alternative for cutting back on saturated fat and calories found in dairy cheese. It’s definitely worth a try!

<strong>About ZENB</strong></p>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/5727b1_2dc4270359b140a081b0966b13744ed3~mv2.webp/v1/fit/w_1000,h_628,al_c,q_80/file.png"></figure>
<p><a href="https://www.awin1.com/cread.php?awinmid=25893&awinaffid=1102079&clickref=PLANTS%2BPERKS&ued=https%3A%2F%2Fzenb.co.uk%2F" target="_blank">ZENB</a> (pronounced ZEN-bee) is an online plant-based food brand on a mission to make delicious plant-forward products accessible and convenient. Their proprietary food development process harnesses the goodness of nature, using as much of the whole plant as possible…skin, seeds, stem, and all.</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p><a href="https://www.awin1.com/cread.php?awinmid=25893&awinaffid=1102079&clickref=PLANTS%2BPERKS&ued=https%3A%2F%2Fzenb.co.uk%2F" target="_blank">ZENB</a> creates award-winning pasta made from 100% yellow peas that’s gluten-free, and high in protein and fibre. Available in 4 shapes, with a fabulous al dente texture, you can pair it with ZENB Gourmet Sauces, which make one of your 5-a-day per serving. Or switch up lunchtime with their NEW Agile Bowls, all you need to do is just add boiling water and enjoy!</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p><a href="https://www.awin1.com/cread.php?awinmid=25893&awinaffid=1102079&clickref=PLANTS%2BPERKS&ued=https%3A%2F%2Fzenb.co.uk%2F" target="_blank"><strong>Use code </strong></a><a href="https://www.awin1.com/cread.php?awinmid=25893&awinaffid=1102079&clickref=PLANTS%2BPERKS&ued=https%3A%2F%2Fzenb.co.uk%2F" target="_blank"><em><strong>PLANTS</strong></em></a><a href="https://www.awin1.com/cread.php?awinmid=25893&awinaffid=1102079&clickref=PLANTS%2BPERKS&ued=https%3A%2F%2Fzenb.co.uk%2F" target="_blank"><strong> at checkout to get 40% off your first ZENB order</strong></a><strong>.</strong></p>
<p><br /></p>
<p>
<strong>References</strong></p>
<ol>
  <li><p>Saget, S. et al 2020. Substituting wheat with chickpea flour in pasta production delivers more nutrition at a lower environmental cost </p></li>
  <li><p>S.V. Angadi et al (2008) Adaptation of alternative pulse and oilseed crops to the semi-arid canadian prairie: seed yield and water use efficiency.</p></li>
  <li><p>Gerber, P. J., H. Steinfeld, B. Henderson, A. Mottet, C. Opio, J. Dijkman, A. Falcucci and G. Tempio. 2013. Tackling climate change through livestock - a global assessment of emissions and mitigation opportunities. Food and Agriculture Organization of the United Nations, Rome. 115 pp.</p></li>
  <li><p>Fernández-Lobato, R. García-Ruiz, F. Jurado, D. Vera. Life cycle assessment, C footprint and carbon balance of virgin olive oils production from traditional and intensive olive groves in southern Spain. J Environ. Manage. 2021 Sept; 293: 112951. doi: 10.1016/j.jenvman.2021.112951</p></li>
</ol>
<p><br /></p>]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Can what you feed your dog help tackle the climate crisis? ]]></title><description><![CDATA[In partnership with THE PACK We all want what’s best for our four-legged companions, but what if the pet food we’ve been taught to trust...]]></description><link>https://www.plantsandperks.com/post/can-what-you-feed-your-dog-help-tackle-the-climate-crisis</link><guid isPermaLink="false">6363916608ea9f82857421e1</guid><pubDate>Thu, 03 Nov 2022 10:05:12 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/5727b1_387ce952a0ea4db5b7578d55a763693e~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><dc:creator>Alice Long</dc:creator><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><br /></p>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/5727b1_387ce952a0ea4db5b7578d55a763693e~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png"></figure>
<p><strong>In partnership with </strong><u><a href="https://thepackpet.com/discount/PLANTS&PERKS30" target="_blank"><strong>THE PACK</strong></a></u> </p>
<p><br /></p>
<p>We all want what’s best for our four-legged companions, but what if the pet food we’ve been taught to trust is not what’s best for our planet and is part of the climate crisis problem?</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p>In recent years, the pet industry has boomed, with more of us owning pets than ever before. There are roughly over 470 million dogs worldwide and they all need feeding at least twice a day - that’s a whole lot of meat being chowed down by our hungry pups! </p>
<p><br /></p>
<p><strong>What effect is pet food having on our planet?</strong></p>
<p>Meaty dog foods are now a major player in the climate crisis. Studies have concluded that animal agriculture is responsible for at least 87% of annual greenhouse gas emissions (1) and as much as 25% of the environmental impact of meat production has been tied to pet food production (2).</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p>In 2020, research from the University of Edinburgh showed that the pet food industry produces almost 3% of the total carbon dioxide (CO2) emissions from farming - that’s the equivalent amount of CO2 produced by a sixth of all global flights (3).</p>
<p>If we look at land use too, studies suggest that an area twice the size of the UK is used to produce meat-based food for cats and dogs, every year (3).</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p><strong>As a pawrent, what can you do to help?</strong></p>
<p>One of the best ways to reduce your pet’s carbon paw print is to introduce <u><a href="https://thepackpet.com/discount/PLANTS&PERKS30" target="_blank"><span style="color: #1155cc;">plant-based dog foods</span></a></u> to their diet. Coined the “flexidogian approach”, this diet is a great way to start introducing plant-based foods to their diet and is all about adding new foods as opposed to excluding any. </p>
<p><br /></p>
<p>Think we’re barking mad and that dogs need meat to survive? Well, maybe you’ve heard of Bramble, a Collie who once held the Guinness World Record for being the oldest living dog at 27 years young? (4) Like her human, Bramble lived on a strict meat-free diet of rice, lentils and organic vegetables. Domestic dogs are omnivores, just like their humans, and can thrive on a complete and balanced meatless diet. They’ve evolved over many thousands of years to digest plant-based foods and can receive all the nutrients they need without meat (5). It’s definitely not something to be sniffed at!</p>
<p>Here are 3 simple ways to start introducing your hound to more <u><a href="https://thepackpet.com/discount/PLANTS&PERKS30" target="_blank"><span style="color: #1155cc;">plant-based, sustainable foods</span></a></u>: </p>
<p><br /></p>
<p><strong>1. Switch their dog treats</strong></p>
<p><br /></p>
<p>Even when you’ve read the science and heard the success stories, it can be nerve-racking to completely change what your dog eats, so why not start off small by making a switch to your dog’s treats.</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p>You can buy delicious <u><a href="https://thepackpet.com/discount/PLANTS&PERKS30" target="_blank"><span style="color: #1155cc;">plant-based dog treats</span></a></u> from independent companies and increasingly from the large pet food brands - or you can simply feed veggies like carrot sticks or cubes of sweet potato to them (believe us, they’ll woof them down!) </p>
<p>Another tip you can try, is to freeze spoonfuls of <u><a href="https://thepackpet.com/discount/PLANTS&PERKS30" target="_blank"><span style="color: #1155cc;">plant-based dog food</span></a></u>, such as that produced by <u><a href="https://thepackpet.com/discount/PLANTS&PERKS30" target="_blank"><span style="color: #1155cc;">THE PACK</span></a></u>, to feed as treats or spread some on a lick mat to keep your pup mentally stimulated.</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p><u><a href="https://thepackpet.com/discount/PLANTS&PERKS30" target="_blank"><span style="color: #1155cc;">Use code PLANTS+PERKS30 at checkout to get 30% off your THE PACK order</span></a></u>.</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p><strong>2. Swap one of their daily meals plant-based dog food</strong></p>
<p><br /></p>
<p>Even if you’re raring to get your pet started on <u><a href="https://thepackpet.com/discount/PLANTS&PERKS30" target="_blank"><span style="color: #1155cc;">meat-free food</span></a></u>, we don’t recommend making a dramatic switch. Just like in humans, sudden changes in diet can lead to stomach upsets, so try transitioning your dog slowly. Plus, not all dogs take to plant-based eating straight away; some pups are addicted to the meaty taste of their usual brand of food, whilst some dogs are just not very food driven at all. It’s best to take it easy with the transition!</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p>Try switching one of their meals for <u><a href="https://thepackpet.com/discount/PLANTS&PERKS30" target="_blank"><span style="color: #1155cc;">plant-based food</span></a></u> or even mixing half <u><a href="https://thepackpet.com/discount/PLANTS&PERKS30" target="_blank"><span style="color: #1155cc;">plant-based food</span></a></u> with half animal meat, then gradually increasing the percentage of the plant-based portion for one of their meals. Just make sure that your dog’s main meal is nutritionally complete and balanced, providing all the nutrients they need for that day. </p>
<p><br /></p>
<p><strong>3. Have a meat-free Mutt-Day</strong></p>
<p><br /></p>
<p>Another way to reduce your dog’s environmental paw print is to do Meat Free Muttday. This is a great opportunity to <u><a href="https://thepackpet.com/discount/PLANTS&PERKS30" target="_blank"><span style="color: #1155cc;">tickle their taste buds with something new</span></a></u> – and maybe try some new vegetable-based dinner options yourself too for Meat Free Monday. If your dog’s anything like ours over here at PLANTS + PERKS, they’ll start begging for courgette as soon as you get out the chopping board! </p>
<p><br /></p>
<p><strong>About THE PACK</strong></p>
<p><br /></p>
<p><u><a href="https://thepackpet.com/discount/PLANTS&PERKS30" target="_blank"><span style="color: #1155cc;">THE PACK</span></a></u> are revolutionising dog food with their 100% nutritionally complete, innovative and science led plant-based dog meals.</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p>Using the highest quality ingredients that are not only better for your dog and their health, but better for the planet too. Winner, winner, plant-based dinner! </p>
<p><br /></p>
<p>THE PACK currently offer three drool-inducing flavours: No-Moo Ragu, No-Cluck Casserole and No-Fishy Dishy all in a 375g can. Available as a multipack or as single flavours.</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p>They welcome flexidogians into their community with open paws. They want to help you make sure your furry friend has the happiest and healthiest life, one meal or one treat at a time. THE PACK is for all pups, whether vegan, vegetarian, pescatarian or flexidogian!</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p><u><a href="https://thepackpet.com/discount/PLANTS&PERKS30" target="_blank"><span style="color: #1155cc;">Use code PLANTS+PERKS30 at checkout to get 30% off your THE PACK order</span></a></u>.</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p>References</p>
<ol>
  <li><p>Gole D. &amp; Watve,A. 2021 Animal Agriculture is the leading cause of climate change - a position paper. Journal of Ecological Society. https://climatehealers.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/JES-Rao.pdf</p></li>
  <li><p>Okin GS (2017) Environmental impacts of food consumption by dogs and cats. PLoS ONE 12(8): e0181301. https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0181301</p></li>
  <li><p>P, Alexander et al 2020. The global environmental paw print of pet food. https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/abs/pii/S0959378020307366?dgcid=author</p></li>
  <li><p>Kim Ahora, “Doggedly On A Veggie Diet,” Times of India, 26 Aug. 2010.</p></li>
</ol>
<p>Knight, A. &amp; Leitsberger, M. 2021. Vegetarian versus Meat-Based Diets for Companion Animals.<u><a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC5035952/" target="_blank"><span style="color: #1155cc;">https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC5035952/</span></a></u></p>
<p><br /></p>]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Help Your Employees Save Money &#38; Be More Sustainable When Working From Home ]]></title><description><![CDATA[Working from home is a great perk and has some fantastic benefits, but it can mean an increase in your employees’ energy bills. During...]]></description><link>https://www.plantsandperks.com/post/help-your-employees-save-money-be-more-sustainable-when-working-from-home</link><guid isPermaLink="false">635a9f3f74f660e3616c74b6</guid><pubDate>Thu, 27 Oct 2022 15:11:19 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/11062b_2dcdf07fcf774dafb34805b47345d8ce~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><dc:creator>Lola Wright</dc:creator><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: left;">Working from home is a great perk and has some fantastic benefits, but it can mean an increase in your employees’ energy bills. During the current cost of living crisis every penny counts so we’ve compiled a list of ways your employees can reduce energy usage when working from home.</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p><br /></p>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/11062b_2dcdf07fcf774dafb34805b47345d8ce~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png"></figure>
<p><br /></p>
<p><br /></p>
<ol>
  <li><p>Offer Flexible Working </p></li>
</ol>
<p><br /></p>
<p>A recent analysis by Uswitch found remote workers typically use 75% more gas and 25% more electricity per day in winter, compared to those who work full time from the office. Where possible, offering your employees the opportunity to work from the office on a flexible basis can combat these costs. </p>
<p><br /></p>
<ol>
  <li><p>Make Office Working Affordable </p></li>
</ol>
<p><br /></p>
<p>A recent survey of 900 hybrid workers by InstantPrint found that 85% agreed working from the office will be more appealing in the coming months, with almost half planning to make the commute to the office to help with energy bills. Help to make this more affordable by reimbursing travel expenses where possible. </p>
<p><br /></p>
<ol>
  <li><p>Encourage the Use of a Smart Meter </p></li>
</ol>
<p>Smart meters can make energy usage more efficient, with an in-home display your employees will be able to track their energy usage in real-time and only be billed for energy they’re actually using. There’s also the added bonus of not having to take and submit readings.With PLANTS + PERKS your employees can get discounts on smart meters - book a call with us to find out more! </p>
<p><br /></p>
<ol>
  <li><p>Help Ease Food Costs</p></li>
</ol>
<p><br /></p>
<p>With many employees opting to return to the office to cut down on energy bills, buying on-the-go meals and hot drinks can become costly. Covering the cost of your employees’ lunch at work can make all the difference. Here at PLANTS + PERKS our users get a FREE LUNCH from Bol every week at their local Tesco - book a call with us to find out more! </p>
<p><br /></p>]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Does sustainability really pay?]]></title><description><![CDATA[According to a new Bain report that analysed Rabobank business lending clients, they found a substantially lower credit risk among the...]]></description><link>https://www.plantsandperks.com/post/does-sustainability-really-pay</link><guid isPermaLink="false">63526796abfe292fed0e1f60</guid><pubDate>Fri, 21 Oct 2022 09:42:07 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/b225ac4d521e4bcdba2901c49f1b5527.jpg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><dc:creator>Ellen Chng</dc:creator><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>According to a new Bain report that analysed Rabobank business lending clients, they found a substantially lower credit risk among the companies that perform well on ESG dimensions.</p>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/b225ac4d521e4bcdba2901c49f1b5527.jpg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png"></figure>
<p>The report goes on to say: </p>
<p><br /></p>
<p>&apos;Recent developments in capital markets also indicate a relationship between sustainability and share price performance. Stocks with higher ESG ratings have outperformed the market and shown greater resilience, a correlation that has persisted through the Covid-19 pandemic.&apos;</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p>There are lots of factors that impact your ESG ratings but had you considered that your employee benefits could be one?</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p>Bringing employees along the sustainability journey is a hugely important element of a much larger commitment to ESG.</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p>Given the above report it is clear that instead of being seen as &apos;fluffy&apos; or &apos;nice&apos; it should be considered an integral part of the commercial agenda.</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p>PLANTS + PERKS can help your organisation achieve their overall ESG goals and turn that commitment into financial success.</p>]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Can great employee benefits turn around the fortunes of a company? Just ask Starbucks...]]></title><description><![CDATA[Back in the 2010s Starbucks was trying to break into China. As a traditionally tea drinking society it had its work cut out. 80% of its...]]></description><link>https://www.plantsandperks.com/post/can-great-employee-benefits-turn-around-the-fortunes-of-a-company-just-ask-starbucks</link><guid isPermaLink="false">63524ece4393d7cde8c59060</guid><pubDate>Fri, 21 Oct 2022 08:02:24 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/11062b_1027102d72ea4135838c771fb72ae6a0~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><dc:creator>Chloe Sweden</dc:creator><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><br /></p>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/11062b_1027102d72ea4135838c771fb72ae6a0~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png"></figure>
<p>Back in the 2010s Starbucks was trying to break into China. As a traditionally tea drinking society it had its work cut out.</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p>80% of its staff were college graduates and attrition was high.</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p>They spent 9 years languishing at the bottom, losing money and not attracting the kind of staff that could lift them out of the doldrums. Shareholders were pleading to cut their losses.</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p>Then they listened to their staff.</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p>In China, parents of the graduates have a strong hand to play in their children&apos;s careers and they were not happy. Why had they paid for a great education only for them to be serving coffee?</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p>So what did Starbucks do? Enter employee benefits, stage right.</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p>Starbucks offered healthcare not only to all their staff, including part-time workers, BUT crucially it extended to their parents too.</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p>They understood that to stand out in China they needed to understand the needs and desires of their employees (and their families) first and foremost.</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p>And guess what? Retention increased, Starbuck&apos;s standing in Chinese society improved and profits soared.</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p>Great benefits can indeed lead to commercial success.</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p>Here at PLANTS + PERKS we don&apos;t just advocate the introduction of sustainable benefits because it&apos;s a nice thing to do- it makes great business sense!</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p>Supporting employees on their sustainability journey is now something your future staff see as an IMPERATIVE and they seek out those companies that best align to their values.</p>
<p><br /></p>]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[5 Tips for Successfully Introducing a New Employee Benefit]]></title><description><![CDATA[Being able to offer a new benefit to employees is an exciting position to be in. After all, a new benefit can not only bring a whole host...]]></description><link>https://www.plantsandperks.com/post/5-tips-for-successfully-introducing-a-new-employee-benefit</link><guid isPermaLink="false">634fae95063058330ea650c9</guid><pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2022 08:00:49 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/11062b_39707fadc2f2494c86fee6e93ba7ed3c~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><dc:creator>Alice Long</dc:creator><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><br /></p>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/11062b_39707fadc2f2494c86fee6e93ba7ed3c~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png"></figure>
<p><br /></p>
<p><br /></p>
<p>Being able to offer a new benefit to employees is an exciting position to be in. After all, a new benefit can not only bring a whole host of advantages to employees, but it can also help employers attract new talent and businesses achieve wider company strategic goals.</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p>However, as with many things in life, preparation is key. So when it comes to introducing the new benefit to employees, having a clear launch and engagement plan in place will help you reap the rewards of a high uptake of the benefit from the beginning and a highly engaged workforce later down the line.</p>
<p> </p>
<p>Here are our five top tips for successfully introducing a new employee benefit:</p>
<p><br /></p>
<ol>
  <li><p><strong>Communication is key</strong></p></li>
</ol>
<p><br /></p>
<p>Communication can play a huge part in how successful the launch of a benefit is. There’s no point offering a new benefit if none of your employees know about it. Therefore in order for a benefit to be truly valuable and triumphant, you need to make sure you communicate early and often so that employees know, understand and engage with the benefit on offer.</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p>During the launch, you’ll need to make sure you have an effective communication strategy in place and that you communicate through multiple channels to reach and notify as many employees as possible. Whether you hold an all-company meeting, post on social media, hand out flyers, put up posters in communal areas or send an all-company email, make sure you spread the word, far and wide.</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p>It’s also important to not just put all your effort into communication at the beginning of the benefit, but to use ongoing communication for weeks/months/years after the launch to keep your new benefit at the forefront of new and existing employees&apos; minds. </p>
<p><br /></p>
<ol>
  <li><p><strong>Make it an occasion</strong></p></li>
</ol>
<p><br /></p>
<p>What better way to rouse up your employees about a new benefit than to organise a fun, informative launch event. Whether it’s a guest speaker, an online cookalong or freebies sent to the office for employees; whatever you decide to go with, make sure it’s relevant to the benefit and will peak interest amongst your workforce. </p>
<p><br /></p>
<p>A good benefits provider will help you organise and host this event to maximise the exposure for your employees. They’ll also be able to provide a walk through of the new benefit to employees to help demonstrate how to access the benefit and the advantages of using it.</p>
<p><br /></p>
<ol>
  <li><p><strong>Consider enlisting some benefit ambassadors</strong></p></li>
</ol>
<p><br /></p>
<p>Often some of the best ‘explainers’ of a new benefit are co-workers. Consider enlisting a group of employees (making sure to include a couple from senior leadership), to not only spread positivity about the new benefit, but to also help others understand the new benefit and answer any questions that they may have.</p>
<p><br /></p>
<ol>
  <li><p><strong>Use your benefit providers expertise</strong></p></li>
</ol>
<p><br /></p>
<p>Rolling out a new benefit may feel a little overwhelming, but with the right benefits provider you’ll be in safe hands. For the launch, leverage external support from your benefits provider to make it really memorable and attractive for employees, which will in turn help them to feel excited about the new benefit. A good provider will be able to provide you with a multitude of marketing materials to use in your own company.</p>
<p><br /></p>
<ol>
  <li><p><strong>Monitor engagement and ask for feedback</strong></p></li>
</ol>
<p><br /></p>
<p>In an ideal world your new benefit will see 100% uptake on the first day it’s launched, however there’s a very high chance that this is unlikely to happen. Work with your benefits provider to set achievable targets and keep track of how many employees are taking advantage of the benefit.</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p>After rolling out the new benefit, you should also be regularly asking employees for feedback. It’s important to find out whether the benefit is meeting their needs and enhancing their lives - collect feedback from those who are taking advantage of the new benefit and those who aren’t too. This feedback can also be extremely useful to a benefits provider, so make sure to pass it onto them. With this feedback, they may be able to make changes to the benefit to ensure uptake and engagement of the new benefit remains high for years to come.</p>
<p><br /></p>]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[3 Ways to involve your staff in your benefits programme]]></title><description><![CDATA[Introducing a new benefits programme can seem like a daunting task. If you have multiple stakeholders and an employee base in the tens of...]]></description><link>https://www.plantsandperks.com/post/3-ways-to-involve-your-staff-in-your-benefits-programme</link><guid isPermaLink="false">634da330e427d65e239e4a0e</guid><pubDate>Mon, 17 Oct 2022 18:53:56 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/11062b_736f6e5c9a0b4229b82552b2cb43a74e~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><dc:creator>Lola Wright</dc:creator><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><br /></p>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/11062b_736f6e5c9a0b4229b82552b2cb43a74e~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png"></figure>
<p>Introducing a new benefits programme can seem like a daunting task. If you have multiple stakeholders and an employee base in the tens of thousands it can seem like an uphill battle to get everyone on board.</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p>The best way is to start early and get employees behind any new benefit you want to introduce.</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p>Here are three ways to make sure you bring them along the journey with you:</p>
<p><br /></p>
<ol>
  <li><p>Go to the relevant employee group. Thinking of bringing childcare support into the workplace- get your Parental employee group to chat through their biggest pain points first. Want to introduce PLANTS + PERKS? Bring your &apos;Green Team&apos; into the conversation early.</p></li>
  <li><p>Survey them!- Everyone LOVES a survey- OK, maybe not but it is an excellent way to get vital feedback. </p></li>
  <li><p>Do a trial- here at PLANTS + PERKS we&apos;re happy to trial our plans for you to see how much your employees will love it and it&apos;s a great way to build excitement and buzz before a launch</p></li>
</ol>
<p><br /></p>
<p><br /></p>]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[How to use employee perks to attract the best talent]]></title><description><![CDATA[When you think of 'perks' what springs to mind? You may be surprised that what you as a benefit or talent leader consider a perk, may not...]]></description><link>https://www.plantsandperks.com/post/how-to-use-employee-perks-to-attract-the-best-talent</link><guid isPermaLink="false">634d9de58c18c764ac66b21e</guid><pubDate>Mon, 17 Oct 2022 18:43:25 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/11062b_c6fcd9a09e3e4f59b3aebd292d7614ca~mv2.jpeg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><dc:creator>Alice Long</dc:creator><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><br /></p>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/11062b_c6fcd9a09e3e4f59b3aebd292d7614ca~mv2.jpeg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png"></figure>
<p>When you think of &apos;perks&apos; what springs to mind? You may be surprised that what you as a benefit or talent leader consider a perk, may not be what your future employee does!</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p>Studies have shown that having your own laptop, being able to work from home or even having a fruit bowl in the office is no longer considered a &apos;perk&apos;!</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p>So, what should and shouldn&apos;t you include on your latest job description that will make you stand out from your competitors?</p>
<p><br /></p>
<ol>
  <li><p>Don&apos;t put technology that is required for work down as a perk- if you need it for your job it&apos;s probably not a benefit to you personally!</p></li>
  <li><p>Do put enhanced parental leave down- 6 months blanket cover isn&apos;t so unusual now so make sure your offering is competitive</p></li>
  <li><p>Don&apos;t make out your holiday allowance is better than it is. Bank Holidays aren&apos;t holidays.</p></li>
  <li><p>Do talk about location- whether remote, hybrid, in-store, in office, factory or on an oil rig- where the role will be based has a huge impact on unrepresented communities like parents and those with extra needs.</p></li>
  <li><p>Genuine benefits- If you have PLANTS + PERKS as an employer you should shout about it on your job descriptions! Talk about the discounts, freebies and prizes. </p></li>
  <li><p>Badges. If you have our Sustainable Employer Badge make sure you display it on your JDs. Gen Zeds will take a pay CUT to work somewhere sustainable so shout about it!</p></li>
</ol>]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[How to support employees through the cost of living crisis]]></title><description><![CDATA[With costs spiralling all around, it can be hard to find innovative ways to boost employee morale beyond blanket pay rises for all. A...]]></description><link>https://www.plantsandperks.com/post/how-to-support-employees-through-the-cost-of-living-crisis</link><guid isPermaLink="false">634d99b3dbef4f262be129cc</guid><pubDate>Mon, 17 Oct 2022 18:22:30 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/11062b_2a55fdcdab4e4e9aa893887b5612bebf~mv2.jpeg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><dc:creator>Chloe Sweden</dc:creator><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>With costs spiralling all around, it can be hard to find innovative ways to boost employee morale beyond blanket pay rises for all. </p>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/11062b_2a55fdcdab4e4e9aa893887b5612bebf~mv2.jpeg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png"></figure>
<p>A starting point could be introducing financial wellbeing measures as a way to help employees manage their personal finances better, or reminding them of the great benefits they can already take advantage of- like eyecare vouchers or cycle to work schemes.</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p>However, more and more, here at PLANTS + PERKS, we are seeing employees seeking new strategies to help support them through increased energy bills and mortgage hikes that don&apos;t take away from a desire to help protect the planet.</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p>Giving employees access to free samples, free weekly meals, reductions on food products and hints and tips on how to cook cheaply and more sustainably can really help underpin other strategies to support employees feeling the pinch.</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p>Why not get the team to come down and hand out free food samples in your organisations? Not only can it be a fun way to get staff to engage in sustainability but it can also cut down food costs that day for employees who take part.</p>]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Why every company needs sustainable benefits]]></title><description><![CDATA[Did you know 53% of the UK’s workforce now say sustainability is an important factor in choosing a company to work for according to an...]]></description><link>https://www.plantsandperks.com/post/why-every-company-needs-sustainable-benefits</link><guid isPermaLink="false">634d74f55dd328ae18093df8</guid><pubDate>Mon, 17 Oct 2022 15:36:29 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/11062b_92904bb948064d5a9be0411b11ee78ad~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><dc:creator>Lola Wright</dc:creator><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Did you know 53% of the UK’s workforce now say sustainability is an important factor in choosing a company to work for according to an Anthesis study?</p>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/11062b_92904bb948064d5a9be0411b11ee78ad~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png"></figure>
<p><br /></p>
<p>And that&apos;s not just the Gen Z&apos;s in early careers- employees up and down the UK are demanding that companies walk the talk when it comes to all things green.</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p><br /></p>
<p>In the past it may have been OK to simply offer a cycle to work scheme to tick a box for a &apos;green initiative&apos; but with more and more flexible and hybrid workers that won&apos;t benefit from the scheme- it won&apos;t go far enough.</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p>Thankfully there are solutions on the market. You can now get some great sustainable pension providers to make the most of your employee pension pots as well as upgrading your fleet to electric.</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p>But when it comes to supporting ALL your employees, from those on the factory floors, to those part-time retail workers, it can be tough to find a one-size fits all.</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p>That&apos;s why we created PLANTS + PERKS. A sustainable benefit that REWARDS all your employees to live healthier, greener lives and gives them something back during the cost of living crisis.</p>
<p><br /></p>]]></content:encoded></item></channel></rss>